<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>natural language processing | Cornelia Ferner</title>
    <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/tag/natural-language-processing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/tag/natural-language-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>natural language processing</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/media/icon_hu5335208573ec51f95dfe6e3211008f96_29473_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>natural language processing</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/tag/natural-language-processing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>(German only) Chatbots, Stereotype und künstliche Moral</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner22c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner22c/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Demo at IJCAI-ECAI 2022</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2022_ijcai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2022_ijcai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IJCAI (International Conference on Artificial Intelligence) is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading conference for AI research and took place between July 23rd and 29th in Vienna this year. Where else but in Vienna would a special track titled &amp;ldquo;AI, arts and creativity&amp;rdquo; be better suited? It was within this track that I could present my Twitter Bot @CaptionBoschBot not only in a talk, but also during a live demo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the motto &amp;ldquo;What does an AI know about arts?&amp;rdquo;, the Bot generates image descriptions for segments taken from Hieronymus Bosch&amp;rsquo;s painting &amp;ldquo;Garden of Earthly Delights&amp;rdquo;. The AI, however, was never trained on art and thus delivers seemingly naive interpretations of the painting. This should demonstrate the limits of AI systems in a playful way and put them to discussion.  The results can also be continuously observed on Twitter, where you can follow, retweet or leave comments on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CaptionBoschBot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@CaptionBoschBot&lt;/a&gt;. The paper can be found in the IJCAI2022 Proceedings: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ijcai.org/proceedings/2022/0694.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.ijcai.org/proceedings/2022/0694.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the conference, Prof. Gerhard Widmer, Program Chair for the track &amp;ldquo;AI, Art and Creativity&amp;rdquo;, gave an impressive keynote with a live demonstration of a four-hand piano performance - with an AI as the accompanying musician.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Captioning Bosch: A Twitter Bot</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner22b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner22b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits from Variational Regularization in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner22a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner22a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does an AI Know about Arts?</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2022_boschbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2022_boschbot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The artworks by Dutch painter Hieronymus Bosch are well known for their incredible wealth of details.
A popular Twitter bot posts small segments of the digitized paintings, thus relieving their density and making them more accessible. 
My Twitter bot &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CaptionBoschBot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CaptioningBoschBot&lt;/a&gt; reacts to these out-of-context image segments and uses them as input for an encoder-decoder model to generate captions that interpret the painted scenes. The encoder-decoder model was trained on photos and realistic pictures and doesn&amp;rsquo;t possess the vocabulary to analyze art. The resulting captions still reveal curious interpretations of otherworldly details.
It uses the out-of-context painting segments as input for an encoder-decoder model to generate captions that interpret the painted objects. 
The generated captions are again posted on Twitter to encourage discussions about Bosch’s masterpieces and the AI technology in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Seeded Latent Dirichlet Allocation for Social Media Based Event Detection and Mapping</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner20b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner20b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Semi-discriminative Approach for Sub-sentence Level Topic Classification on a Small Dataset</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner20a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner20a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effectiveness of the Max Entropy Classifier for Feature Selection</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/schnoll19a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/schnoll19a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Presentation: Sub-sentence Level Topic Classification</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2019_ecmlpkdd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2019_ecmlpkdd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;sub-sentence-level-topic-classification&#34;&gt;Sub-sentence Level Topic Classification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper aims at identifying sequences of words related to specific product components in online product 
reviews. A reliable baseline performance for this topic classification problem is given by a Max Entropy 
classifier which assumes independence over subsequent topics. 
However, the reviews exhibit an inherent structure on the document level allowing to frame the task
as sequence classification problem. Since more flexible models from the class of Conditional Random Fields 
were not competitive because of the limited amount of training data available, we propose using a 
Hidden Markov Model instead and decouple the training of transition and emission probabilities. 
The discriminating power of the Max Entropy approach is used for the latter. 
Besides outperforming both standalone methods as well as more generic models such as linear-chain 
Conditional Random Fields, the combined classifier is able to assign topics on subsentence level 
although labeling in the training data is only available on sentence level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Extraction Engine for Sentiment-Topic Matching in Product Intelligence Applications</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner17a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner17a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
