<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>natural language processing | Cornelia Ferner</title>
    <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/tag/natural-language-processing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/tag/natural-language-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>natural language processing</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>natural language processing</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/tag/natural-language-processing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Captioning Bosch: A Twitter Bot</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner22b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner22b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits from Variational Regularization in Language Models</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner22a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner22a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does an AI Know about Arts?</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2022_boschbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2022_boschbot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The artworks by Dutch painter Hieronymus Bosch are well known for their incredible wealth of details.
A popular Twitter bot posts small segments of the digitized paintings, thus relieving their density and making them more accessible. 
My Twitter bot &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CaptionBoschBot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CaptioningBoschBot&lt;/a&gt; reacts to these out-of-context image segments and uses them as input for an encoder-decoder model to generate captions that interpret the painted scenes. The encoder-decoder model was trained on photos and realistic pictures and doesn&amp;rsquo;t possess the vocabulary to analyze art. The resulting captions still reveal curious interpretations of otherworldly details.
It uses the out-of-context painting segments as input for an encoder-decoder model to generate captions that interpret the painted objects. 
The generated captions are again posted on Twitter to encourage discussions about Bosch’s masterpieces and the AI technology in general.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Project &#34;Chatbots for Higher Education&#34; Starts</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2022_schnatterbuchse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2022_schnatterbuchse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-project-chatbots-for-higher-education-starts&#34;&gt;Research Project &amp;ldquo;Chatbots for Higher Education&amp;rdquo; Starts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2022, the interdisciplinary research project &amp;ldquo;Chatbots for Higher Education&amp;rdquo; starts, in which I and Prof. Dr. Eva Lienbacher (Business degree program) are exploring ways of applying chatbots for educational purposes.
Chatbots can be applied to support with different teaching tasks, such as assisting with FAQs, mentoring or the simulation of expert interviews in professional settings, where the chatbot plays the role of customers, patients etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a two year period, two proof-of-concepts and a use case study will be developed and implemented together with our students.
The target audience primarily are students from four of our degree programs in engineering and business and social sciences.
In transfer workshops, we will share our knowledge with a broader audience.
The findings will also help in establishing new academic partnerhsips and acquire funding for new research projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is funded by SUAS&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Zukunftsfonds&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information: &lt;a href=&#34;https://its.fh-salzburg.ac.at/forschung/forschungsprojekte/projektseite/schnatterbuechse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ITS department&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Seeded Latent Dirichlet Allocation for Social Media Based Event Detection and Mapping</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner20b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner20b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Semi-discriminative Approach for Sub-sentence Level Topic Classification on a Small Dataset</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner20a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner20a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effectiveness of the Max Entropy Classifier for Feature Selection</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/schnoll19a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/schnoll19a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Presentation: Sub-sentence Level Topic Classification</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2019_ecmlpkdd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/post/2019_ecmlpkdd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;sub-sentence-level-topic-classification&#34;&gt;Sub-sentence Level Topic Classification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper aims at identifying sequences of words related to specific product components in online product 
reviews. A reliable baseline performance for this topic classification problem is given by a Max Entropy 
classifier which assumes independence over subsequent topics. 
However, the reviews exhibit an inherent structure on the document level allowing to frame the task
as sequence classification problem. Since more flexible models from the class of Conditional Random Fields 
were not competitive because of the limited amount of training data available, we propose using a 
Hidden Markov Model instead and decouple the training of transition and emission probabilities. 
The discriminating power of the Max Entropy approach is used for the latter. 
Besides outperforming both standalone methods as well as more generic models such as linear-chain 
Conditional Random Fields, the combined classifier is able to assign topics on subsentence level 
although labeling in the training data is only available on sentence level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article Abstract&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Extraction Engine for Sentiment-Topic Matching in Product Intelligence Applications</title>
      <link>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner17a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cornelia-ferner.github.io/publication/ferner17a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
